Alistair Prosser; Curriculum Vitae

31 Stanhope Street, Hereford, HR40HA Alistair.prosser@gmail.com 07792988391

Summary

I graduated from the University of Sheffield in July 2016 with a second class honours in Bioengineering and have work experience in the service industry, in the field of engineering, and 7 years of teaching experience with a specialty in physics. I have enjoyed my time working as a teacher, however I am looking to progress into a different role within the education sector. I am friendly and sociable, and enjoy building relationships and networking with colleagues and members of the public. Education has been my passion for 8 years, and I firmly believe that every student is entitled to the best quality education possible.

Education

- PGCE in Physics University of York September 2016 to June 2017
- BEng in Bioengineering University of Sheffield September 2012 to July 2016
- HND in mechanical engineering Worcester college of technology September 2011 to June 2012
- HNC in electrical engineering Hereford College of technology September 2007 to June 2009
- NVQ level 3 in electrical engineering and design Hereford Group Training Association

Work Experience

KS3 Coordinator – Earl Mortimer College and Sixth Form

September 2024-Present

I was employed at Earl Mortimer College to design an entirely new KS3 curriculum for years 7,8 and 9. In addition to this I have been a full time teacher, recorded and assessed KS3 data, and targeted intervention where needed.

Assistant Curriculum Lead of Science – Whittington Green School

September 2023 to July 2024

In September 2023 I progressed to curriculum lead of science. A role in which I processed data from exam results and in class tests, as well as conducting performance reviews whilst helping to manage a busy science department.

Teacher of Science – Whittington Green School

September 2018- July 2024

I have worked diligently as a teacher for 7 years, planning and delivering excellent quality lessons, managing students, and providing feedback and support.

Teacher of Science – Hope Valley College

September 2017 – June 2018

In my first teaching role I provided maternity cover for a teacher of biology where I took on her classes and helped her Y11 students through their GCSEs.

Junior design engineer – Bijur Delimon International

June 2008 – August 2012

My key responsibilities whilst working for the above company were designing lubrication and cooling systems from first principles, meeting strict deadlines, working as part of a vast team, and communicating effectively with customers, suppliers, and internal and external manufacturers. Whilst employed with Bijur Delimon international, I completed an apprenticeship at NVQ level 3, and several courses in SolidWorks computer aided design software.